[train rumbles]
[narrator] In the forests of the Dentora
region of the Republic of Padokea
lies a dormant volcano
measuring 3,722 meters high.
It is known as Kukuroo Mountain.
It is home to a family
of famous assassins, the Zoldyck family.
Visitors arrive every day,
in hopes of catching
a glimpse of the mansion
which has never been seen.
It's one of this nation's
most popular tourist attractions.
[theme music plays]
[Zebro] Well, how long
will you be staying here?
Until we see Killua!
And we're not leaving a second before!
[chuckles]
[Zebro] All right, then. Follow me.
THE X GUARD'S X DUTY
[narrator] Gon and his friends
have begun to confront
the obstacles that they must overcome
in order to reunite with Killua.
They head toward their destination
with no idea what awaits them.
[Zebro] Here we are.
These are the servants' quarters.
It's getting pretty late...
so, you can stay here tonight.
[rumbling]
-[Kurapika] Uh...
-[Zebro] Please, come on in.
Hey, anybody home?
[man]
Guests, huh? Don't see that every day.
[Zebro] This is Seaquant.
He works with me here at the estate.
[Gon] Good evening.
Hmm.
Zebro doesn't take a liking
to just anybody.
Make yourselves at home.
Though in this house,
that's easier said than done.
You wanna see young Master Killua?
[laughs] Now, that's pretty funny.
[Leorio] Actually, we're dead serious.
Then let me give you some advice.
Give up now and go home.
What did you say?
[Seaquant] Zebro told you
about the Testing Gate, right?
If you wanna know what this place is like,
that's an example.
[Gon] It won't be easy. We get that.
But still, I'm not leaving yet.
Not until I see Killua!
Before, when he was in trouble,
I wasn't there for him
like I should've been.
If I was... If I'd just been there...
I know I could have stopped him.
He's my friend,
and he's really important to me, okay?
[Zebro chuckles] I understand.
In that case, why don't you do
some training while you're here?
-What do you mean?
-Hey now, Zebro.
[Zebro] Listen to me, Gon.
You three can try to open
the door together.
There's nothing wrong with teamwork.
And with a little bit of training,
it should be possible.
How about it?
I don't like the idea of being tested.
But if there's truly no other way...
I guess we'll just have to do it!
Yeah!
All right. Then, I'm going to need
all three of you to put something on.
[Gon, Kurapika and Leorio] Huh?
[Leorio grunting]
[groans] How is this so heavy?
[Zebro] It weighs 50 kilograms.
Wear it at all times,
except when you're sleeping.
[Leorio groans]
I'll make it heavier
as you get used to it.
[Leorio yells]
[Zebro] Here, have some tea.
[Leorio grunting] What the--?
[all grunting]
The cups weigh 20 kilograms.
And this teapot weighs 40.
What?
[Zebro] All the furniture
and utensils in this house
weigh over 20 kilograms each.
[Kurapika] I see what you're getting at.
So, this will serve as training.
[Seaquant] What's the point?
You know they're just gonna give up
in two or three days.
What was that?
Oh, Seaquant, unless I'm mistaken,
your shift's already started, hasn't it?
Yeah, I think you're right.
[Leorio growls]
[door rumbling]
Sorry about that.
He really isn't such a bad person.
Oh, by the way, where's the bathroom?
Right through that door over there.
[Leorio panting]
Let me guess. The bathroom door is also...
Of course. That door weighs 500 kilograms.
Five-hundred?
What? You're kidding me!
I'm gonna spring a leak!
[footsteps approaching]
[water drips]
[Kikyo] Kalluto, dear, open the door.
[Kikyo]
Kil, have you learned your lesson yet?
[Milluki] It's no use, Mama.
He isn't even the least bit sorry.
-We need to make him suffer more.
[fan cracks]
-Enough! Shut your mouth, Milluki!
-[Milluki huffs]
[Kikyo] Kil, darling, why don't you stop
being so stubborn
and just say that you're sorry?
Oh, and about that friend of yours.
His name is Gon, isn't it?
He'd be better off leaving,
but it sounds like he wants
to try his hand at the Testing Gate.
Gon, he's... he's here?
Milluki! You said far too much.
Now, you see, Kil--
-Why the hell didn't you tell me?
-[whip cracks]
Don't you ever talk to Mom
like that again!
I told you to shut your mouth!
I didn't think telling you was necessary.
He can't open the gate,
not in a million years.
-[Killua] He will.
-[gasps]
He'll do it. I know it.
Well, isn't that absolutely divine?
However, he won't make it here.
I can promise you that.
[Killua] Gon will.
He can do it. He'll prove you wrong.
No question.
He'll definitely make it here.
[Leorio] Gon, wait.
You just watch, okay?
But why?
You need to let your arm
heal properly, first.
If Kurapika and I can open it ourselves,
you don't have to worry.
Let us handle it.
Fine.
-You ready, Kurapika?
-Yeah!
[both grunting]
[Seaquant] Come on, you're only
wasting your time.
[Kurapika] No use. It won't budge.
[Leorio] Damn it!
But we only just started training.
If we work hard enough,
I know we can do it!
[Kurapika]
I wish I could share your optimism.
[chuckles]
[both grunting]
[snoring]
[grunting]
[both grunting]
[both panting]
I'm telling you,
this is never gonna work.
You're just kidding yourselves,
you know that.
Well, if you're so sure,
quit watching and go do your job.
[Kurapika] Gon is one of us.
[sighs] And he's made it clear
that he wishes to see his friend.
Quite clear.
It's only right to help him
achieve his goal.
[Leorio] Let's give it another shot!
[Kurapika] Yeah!
[both grunting]
[Seaquant] Oh, give me a break.
You can't keep pushing mindlessly.
Get your timing in sync.
You have to push both doors
simultaneously with everything you've got.
Otherwise, it'll never open.
[Zebro chuckles]
[Leorio] Get our timing in sync.
[Kurapika] Push both doors simultaneously,
and with all our might.
You ready?
One!
And two!
[both] Three!
[both grunting]
[all gasp]
[Gon] Leorio! Kurapika!
It moved a little.
HUNTER GLOSSARY
TESTING GATE
[man] What's that?
The Testing Gate? Are you certain?
And?
[Seaquant] Oh, well, I just wanted
to let you know, is all.
Very well.
Why does he always have to be
so damn gruff?
[Leorio grunting]
Hey, you two. Look, why don't you try
taking those vests off, today?
Huh? Well, don't mind if I do.
All right, now we'll be able
to open the gate for sure!
-Let's do this, Kurapika!
-Right!
One, and two...
[both] Three!
[both grunting]
[gasps]
[Leorio] Damn it.
That's as far as it'll go!
You can't give up yet.
Keep pushing!
Okay, I'm with you!
Gon!
What do you think you're doing?
Your arm, remember?
It's okay. It's healed now.
[Kurapika] What, already?
-[Leorio] Are you sure, Gon?
-[Gon] Yep!
So anyway, we gotta match our breathing?
-Uh, that's right.
-Well, let's push.
Here goes!
Ready!
Get set!
Go!
[all grunting]
-It's opening.
-[Zebro chuckles]
[gasps]
[Gon grunts]
[Gon] Ow!
[both panting]
It opened.
[Leorio] Hell yeah!
-[Kurapika] We really did it, Gon!
-[Gon] Uh-huh!
[Zebro] Now then, just follow this path
and head toward the mountain.
The mansion should be up there somewhere.
Never been there myself,
which is kind of embarrassing,
considering I've worked here for 20 years.
I'm sorry I can't be of any more help.
No, sir, you have been.
Mr. Zebro, Seaquant,
thanks for everything.
[chuckles]
[Gon] Thanks again!
See you later!
[Zebro] They're really something.
Those three might actually have
what it takes to reach the mansion.
[snickers] It's not gonna happen.
They'll die for sure.
Are you speaking from your experience
back then?
-[wind rustles]
-[birds squawk]
[Seaquant] A single apprentice butler
wiped us out to the last man.
And that made one thing
painfully clear:
that I'd gotten myself in
way over my head.
I recall you were so impressed
that you asked for a job here.
Yeah, well, excuse me.
But the bosses and workers here
are monsters. Every last one.
And once you step onto their turf...
[Kikyo] The Testing Gate opened?
[butler] Yes, ma'am.
[Kikyo]
This is a critical time for Killua.
We simply cannot allow anyone near him!
Especially unnecessary distractions
like friends.
-Is that clear?
-[butler] Yes, ma'am.
Please leave now.
You're trespassing on private property.
I can't allow you to pass
without permission.
[Gon] But we called ahead,
and we came in through the Testing Gate.
[Canary] The butler's quarters did not
give you permission to enter.
What the heck do we need to do
to get permission?
I even told them I was Killua's friend
and everything.
Who knows?
No one has ever received permission.
[Gon] Then I guess we're gonna
have to trespass!
I suppose so.
In any case,
this is where I draw the line.
Take one step past it and I will remove
you by force if necessary.
Damn it!
[Gon] Leorio! Kurapika!
Stay where you are.
I'll handle this.
Ow!
Look, we didn't come here
to fight anyone.
We just want to see Killua.
Your motives don't matter.
I have my orders, and it is my duty
to follow them.
Try all you like.
I'll never let you pass.
[Gon] I will pass.
I'm gonna see Killua!
[Canary] Welcome home, Master Killua.
[Killua] Yeah.
-I made one.
-Huh?
[Killua] A friend.
[staff thudding]
Stop right there.
Please go away!
Why won't you just give up?
You know it's pointless!
Please stop him! You're his friends!
Why...?
[Gon] What's the big deal?
I just came here to see my friend.
The only reason I'm here
is to see Killua!
[gasps]
[Gon] So why are you making me
go through all of this?
[birds cawing]
-[Gon] Hey.
-[Canary gasps]
[Gon] I crossed the line.
Shouldn't you hit me?
I can tell you're different from Mike.
You may be trying to cover up
your feelings,
but you still have a heart.
When I mentioned Killua's name,
your eyes softened, just for a moment.
[Canary sniffling] Please...
Help him. Help Master--
[glass crackles]
[all gasping]
[Kikyo] Honestly...
What was that servant babbling about?
She made it sound
like we were being mean to Killua.
How rude. She's just a bloody apprentice.
And you must be Gon.
Illumi told me all about you.
Killua is aware that you've been
on the premises for some time now.
I have a message from Killua
that he asked me to relay to you.
"Thank you for coming.
I'm happy that you did.
But I can't see you right now.
I'm sorry."
[narrator] Gon and his friends have
finally made it inside the Zoldyck estate.
But now, they face
their greatest obstacle yet:
a sad message from Killua himself,
saying that he cannot see them.
[theme music plays]
[Gon] Next time.
"The Zoldyck Family."
[Gon] Who is Killua to you, anyway?
[Kalluto] My big brother!